PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hey Pete.
- 嘿皮特。
- Oh hey Val.
- 嘿瓦尔。
- How's it goin'?
- 近况如何'？
- You know what, I'm havin' a really bad day.
- 你知道，我要有一个非常糟糕的一天。
- What happened?
- 发生了什么？
- See what Val's saying when she says, "What happened,"
- 看看瓦尔的说法时，她说，“发生了什么事，”
is, tell me a story.
是，告诉我一个故事。
And that's actually what this season
而这实际上这个赛季什么
of Pixar in a Box is all about.
皮克斯在一个盒子是怎么一回事。
To make a movie here at Pixar takes years,
为了使电影在这里皮克斯需要数年时间，
but it all starts with a story.
但是这一切都始于一个故事。
Humans have been telling stories since we
人类一直在讲，因为我们的故事
could speak, probably before.
或许可以说话之前。
We tell stories around the campfire,
我们告诉围着篝火故事，
we write plays, we write novels, short stories.
我们写剧本，我们写小说，短篇故事。
We make movies, we take photographs, tweet to each other,
我们拍电影，我们拍照，鸣叫对方，
the list goes on.
这样的例子不胜枚举。
The power of story is that it has an ability
故事的力量在于它有能力
to connect with people on an emotional level.
与人连接在情感层面上。
One of the things you hear all the time,
一个你听到所有的时间的事情，
this advice, is write what you know.
这个建议，是写你知道什么。
Now, as a kid I was like, I don't want
现在，作为一个孩子，我当时想，我不想
to write about suburban Minnesota, that's boring.
写明尼苏达州的郊区，这没意思。
I wanna write about explosions
我想写写爆炸
and monsters and car chases.
和怪物和汽车追逐。
Well, what that actually means is,
那么，什么是真正的意思是，
yeah go ahead and write about monsters
是的继续和写怪物
and explosions and car chases, but put something into
和爆炸和追车，但东西放在
it that talks about your own life, how you feel.
它是谈自己的生活，你的感觉如何。
Do you feel scared?
你觉得害怕吗？
Do you feel alone?
你是否感到孤独？
Something from your own life will make
从自己的生活中的东西会令
that story come alive and not just be
这个故事活灵活现，而不是仅仅是
a boring car chase.
一个无聊的汽车追逐。
- (mumbles)
- （喃喃自语）
- When I started directing Monsters, Incorporated,
- 当我开始指挥怪兽日注册成立，
the way I would pitch it is, it's
我会选中它是这样的，它是
about a monster who scares kids for a living.
关于谁害怕孩子为生的怪物。
That's his job.
这是他的工作。
He clocks in, he clocks out, he eats donuts
他在计时，他计时了，他吃甜甜圈
and talks about union dos, and we thought
而有关联合DOS的会谈，我们认为
that was a pretty funny idea.
这是一个非常有趣的想法。
And sure enough, when I would tell it
果然，当我告诉它
to people, they would smile.
对人来说，他们会微笑。
But when we told the story as a film,
但是，当我们告诉这个故事作为电影，
people started getting bored and restless
人们开始感到厌烦和不安
and they're like, "I don't understand
他们会说：“我不明白
"what this movie's about."
“这是什么电影的约。”
Well, what I finally figured out was
好了，我终于想通了，是
that it's actually not about a monster who scares kids,
它实际上不是关于谁害怕孩子一个怪物，
it's about a man becoming a father.
它是关于一个男人成为父亲。
(laughing)
（笑）
That was what was happening to me.
这是发生了什么事给我。
So, why write about what you know?
那么，为什么写，你知道吗？
Well, it's because, probably what happened
嗯，这是因为，很可能发生了什么
to you made you feel some particular way.
你让你感觉有些特定的方式。
And what you're trying to do really when you tell
而且你想，当你告诉做什么真
a story, is to get the audience to have that same feeling.
一个故事，是让观众有同样的感觉。
One of the big revelations for me telling stories,
其中一个很大的启示，我讲故事，
is how much work they are, really.
是多少，他们的工作是，真的。
I always thought, you would just tell
我一直以为，你只会告诉
the story once, and it would be perfect.
故事一次，这将是完美的。
And geniuses like Walt Disney or Miyazaki,
而天才像迪斯尼或宫崎，
this brilliance comes out of their head once,
这个辉煌出来他们的头的一次，
and there it is.
它就在那里。
Well the truth is, our stories don't always come
那么事实是，我们的故事并不总是
out exactly perfectly the first time,
确切完美的第一次，
or the second time, or the third time,
或所述第二时间或第三时间，
or the fourth time, up to the 30th time.
或第四次，上升到30次。
And so you keep going again and again.
所以你保持一遍又一遍去。
And only after retelling the story many,
只有经过复述故事很多，
many times, does it really sparkle.
很多时候，它真的闪闪发光。
This season of Pixar in a Box is
这在一个盒子皮克斯的季节
about how we at Pixar tell our stories,
关于我们皮克斯如何告诉我们的故事，
in hopes that it will inspire you to tell yours.
在希望它会激励你要告诉你的。
- But, seriously, what happened?
- 但是，严重的是，发生了什么？
- Oh, oh, so the first thing.
- 哦，哦，这样的第一件事。
I get to my desk, right?
我得到我的办公桌上，对不对？
It's eight o'clock in the morning... aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
这是早上八点钟...  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox